

# Sanket Sandipkumar Amin

Nationality: Indian Date of birth: 20/12/2001 Gender: Male

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/thesanketamin/

② IEEE Xplore Author's Page: <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/author/37087474414">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/author/37087474414</a>

Website: <a href="https://sanketamin.tech/">https://sanketamin.tech/</a>

• Home: Anand (India)

# **ABOUT ME**

I graduated with a B.Tech. degree in Electronics and Communication Engineering from Birla Vishvakarma Mahavidyalaya in 2023. I developed a passion for Machine Learning, the Internet of Things (IoT) and Embedded Systems during my studies and completed several projects using hardware like Raspberry Pi Model 4 and NVIDIA Jetson Nano, and software technologies like Keras and TensorFlow platform used with Python. One of my projects, Automatic Number Plate Recognition (ANPR) for Toll Tax Collection, won the second runner-up position at the Annual Project Expo 2023 and was published in the IEEE Xplore digital library. My other achievements also include securing a winning position in the 2022 Robo-Race Competition at the Udaan Annual Festival.

As an Associate Technical Consultant at Intech Systems, I worked with clients to design, implement, and support solutions using Microsoft Power Platform and Microsoft Azure OpenAI. I leverage my skills and knowledge in these technologies to create custom applications, automate workflows, and optimize business processes.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Associate Technical Consultant**

**Intech Systems Pvt. Ltd.** [ 06/2023 – 01/2024 ]

City: Ahmedabad | Country: India

- Objective: Work on Microsoft Power Platform and Azure OpenAl to provide digital business solutions like workflow automation and web applications
- Projects: HR ChatBot, Training Management System (TMS) application

# **Web Development & Designing Intern (Internship)**

**The Sparks Foundation** [ 06/2022 – 08/2022 ]

Country: India

- Objective: To have an industry-level understanding of website designing
- Final Project: Personal Portfolio Website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

# **Embedded Engineer Intern (Internship)**

Reliable Electronics (now Electrofly) [ 06/2021 - 07/2021 ]

City: Anand | Country: India

- Objective: Work on MCU coding on Arduino IDE and circuit designing using simulation tools like Proteus Design Suite
- Final Project: Arduino UNO R3 based smart parking system

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# B.Tech. in Electronics & Communication Engineering (Birla Vishvakarma Mahavidyalaya Engineering College)

**Gujarat Technological University** [ 08/2019 – 05/2023 ]

City: Anand | Country: India | Final grade: 8.04 CPI

# 12th (Zen School)

**Central Board of Higher Secondary Education (CBSE)** [ 04/2018 – 03/2019 ]

City: Anand | Country: India | Final grade: 75.2 %

# 10th (Zen School)

**Central Board of Higher Secondary Education (CBSE)** [ 04/2016 – 03/2017 ]

City: Anand | Country: India | Final grade: 8.4 CGPA

# **PUBLICATIONS**

ANPR Based Toll Tax Collection System D. C. Dalwadi and S. Amin, "ANPR Based Toll Tax Collection System," 2023 IEEE 11th Region 10 Humanitarian Technology Conference (R10-HTC), Rajkot, India, 2023, pp. 53-57, doi: 10.1109/R10-HTC57504.2023.10461835

# **PROJECTS**

**Automatic Number Plate Recognition System (ANPR)** TensorFlow-based machine learning project used to detect and extract vehicle's number/license plate for toll tax collection.

**Automatic Ignition Locking System** ESP32 based project used to implement a cost-saving alcohol detection system that is useful to avoid road accidents, caused by incapable drivers, by locking the vehicle's ignition system.

# **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Computer Vision / Machine Learning / Embedded Systems: Embedded C / IoT(Internet of Things) / Problem-solving / Technical Writing

#### **CERTIFICATION & COURSES**

**Machine Learning Specialization - Coursera** 

**Python Programming - LinkedIn Learning** 

**Data Manipulation in Python - Udemy** 

Introduction to the Internet of Things and Embedded Systems - Coursera

**ARM Microcontroller - Bharat Acharya Education** 

Microsoft Certified: Power Platform Fundamentals - Microsoft

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Gujarati

Other language(s):

**English** Hindi

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C1 LISTENING C2 READING C1 WRITING B1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user